===============================
Proof Assistant Version History
===============================

v 1.5 (current)
===============
- 2018 code review

v 1.4.2 (Bugfixes)
==================
- Fixed problem with parsing inputs with quantifiers. You no longer need spaces or brackets
- Fixed bug where \sequent input in TeX input wouldn't work with no premises
- Friendly inputs with spaces no longer create bracket-match errors
- Closing using x now saves settings
- Tweaked the TeX output to (hopefully) accomodate larger fonts
- Fixed problem where existential introduction would fail to identify a matching line

v 1.4.1 (Bugfixes)
==================
- Fixed bug where app would open files from command line properly
- Fixed problem with nominal elimination
- Fixed problem with "skipped" terms (when the context was invisible)
- Changed the name of the .config file to pa.config
- Implemented second order logic methods for universal introduction and existential elimination
- Implemented the ability to display default diamond boxes
- Fixed a problem with the line numbers for axioms
- My axioms are now saved in presets

v 1.4.0 (Modal/Hybrid Logic, Numerous Changes, Bugfixes) (current)
========================================================
- Export to text now supports identity boxes
- Export to text now displays lines for scopes/boxes
- Same Line was missing in 1.3.3. It has been restored and given a checkbox in the rule palette
- Bugfixes with save/open
- A proof can now be exported to an animated gif. This loops through the entire proof, pausing at the end
- Starting a proof from TeX code now detects whether an operator is unary or binary from the number of arguments given
- Fixed a problem where blank lines would reappear after opening the rule palette
- Added the ability to use digits for numbers in Friendly input for Q
- You can now specify your own axioms, in addition to Q. These are specified under Options -> My Axioms
- Fixed a bug with existential rules when applying replacements with certain variables (this would cause weird behaviour with the operators)
- Added some keyboard shortcuts for the Friendly Inputs. Use Alt as a mask for the keys in the following table:
	∨ - v
	⊃ - .
	≡ - 3
	∀ - a
	∃ - e
	⋅ - 8
	↓ - \
	(some shortcuts seem weird, but look at their Shift equivalents)
- Added support for Modal/Hybrid Logic
	-> The following rules have been added:
		-> Box introduction/elimination
		-> @ introduction/elimination
		-> diamond introduction/elimination
		-> nominal introduction/elimination
		-> self-reference introduction/elimnation
	-> All lines are now given a context. You can set this to be visible or invisible via the rule palette.
	-> To specify a context, prepend the line with [context]:. So, to create a line p with context b, input b:p
	-> You must use the above shortcut (or copy/paste from this readme) to get ↓. Put ↓x Fx or whatever.
	-> For a box operator, put [r] or [s] or whatever.
	-> For a diamond operator, put <r> or <s> or whatever.
	-> For an @ operator, put @t p or whatever.
- Added support for (simple) second-order logic
	-> You can use universal elimination and existential introduction with propositions.


v 1.3.3 (Bugfixes, Arity changes, Small features)
=================================================
- Fixed problem where Q remained as the current system for one undo too many
- Fixed a problem where Q axioms and identity box lines were displaying the wrong line numbers in certain proof exports
- The Q axioms no longer disappear in certain situations
- Zoom with identity boxes no longer goes funny
- The thickness of identity box and scope lines now increases with zoom
- Mentions to the previous proof system method have been removed
- Identity boxes, universals shortcuts and automatic parameters are now incoporated into presets
- Fixed a problem where an error would occur if you failed to select a preset upon first starting
- The term selector panel now always shows terms instead of numbers
- Q axioms can now be selected from the keyboard
- An undo step has been added before the initial current goal is selected
- Changes have been made to the handling of arities
	-> An arities button on the status bar keeps track of the terms used and unused in its tooltip.
	-> Clicking this button opens the settings dialogue
	-> The arity list in settings is split in two - used terms and unused terms
	-> You can change unused terms but not used terms
	-> Closing settings now refreshes the line in the proof, to respect the new arities
	-> Terms become used if they are in a line that was a current goal or resource for an operation
- Implemented uneditable proofs
	-> A proof can be saved as a .ndu file. Any .ndp file can be changed to a .ndu file
	-> .ndu files will be opened as uneditable proofs. All selections and buttons will be disabled, the proof will open at the beginning and next and previous buttons will appear
	-> The user is able to step through the proof



v 1.3.2 (Proof System Changes)
==============================
- Changed how proof systems are applied
	-> Proof systems (nj, nk etc.) are now seens as bundles of rule options
	-> You can access all the rules from Options, Rule Palette
		-> From here, you can select which rules you want, choose a preset or save your current selections to a preset
		-> The options you select in the rule palette govern what rules are available in the proof panel
	-> A new status bar has been implemented
		-> This shows the weakest system(s) that support the current proof
		-> This also shows the current ruleset (i.e., the preset that you have selected in the rule palette)
	-> The current preset is saved with the proof
	-> The current ruleset is saved with the proof
- This release is likely to be buggy


v 1.3.1 (Bugfixes)
==================
- Changed copy to clipboard mechanism in attempt to play nice with OSX
- Fixed bug where the proof system would not update upon opening a proof
- Zoom now zooms dynamically (yay!)
- Added shortcuts for save, open, close, export, export to TeX, new from TeX code, About
- Shifted the location of identity box buttons to the right
- Changing to and from Q and PA now updates the proof with the relevant axioms
- Friendly Input now permits ∀x∀y x+y=y+x style inputs
- Fixed bug when cutting a line inside an identity box
- Fixed a problem in identity elimination, where clicking "Cancel" would give a "rule not applicable" error.
- Fixed problem where Q axioms were selectable as goals after proof open
- Corrected the formality of one error message
- Fixed problem where arities were not updated after proof open


v 1.3.0 (Major Release)
=======================
- Fixed brackets for + and times. These now differentiate between s(x)+y and s(x+y).
- Fixed a problem where the subtitution instance dialogue would appear for no reason.
- Added cut line
- Added redo
- Dead-end actions will now present a message box
- Dead-end actions will no longer add to the undo stack
- Implemented save and open. These work on .ndp files.
- Brackets are now displayed around + and times
- A friendlier WYSIWYG input has been designed
- One line assumptions are now supported
- Settings are now persistent. A file called .paconfig is read (if it exists) on start, and overwritten/created when you click file-> close
- Ctrl/Command+C now copies a png of the proof to the clipboard


v 1.2.2 (Bugfixes, Induction)
=============================
- Input with \cdot now works
- Fixed problem where the settings dialog would not save if a proof has not been started
- The settings window is no longer always on top
- Implemented negation elimination with shortcuts
- Fixed bug that caused rules to fail when + was present
- Possible terms are now checked to make sure that they have balanced brackets
- The substitute LtR or RtL dialog now parses lines
- Fixed problem where the subsitution instance selection dialogue would appear when not needed
- Implemented Induction
   -> To use induction, change to PA under options
   -> The IND button appears where the == button would be
   -> The == button has precedence
   -> Applying induction creates a line with 0, obtains a new term and creates an assumption with the term and an assumption end with s+the term. The current goal is justified.
   -> The IND button should only appear for universal quantifiers
- Added more error warnings, the new ones are not user friendly but might give an idea what's wrong


v 1.2.1 (Bugfixes, Q)
=====================
- Corrected problem where not all terms would be tested for equivalence elimination
- Adjusted column positions to match text widths
- Introduced Magic Mode (under Edit), which steps through every automatic step possible (up to 10 steps). This is experimental.
- Included a setting in Settings to change the symbols used
- Implemented a choice option when multiple instances of a term to be substituted appear in a line
- Changed the input to universally comma separated.
- Commas within () are now supported.
- Fixed a problem where line numbers would stop incrementing after an identity box was created.
- Introduced Robinson Arithmetic
   -> \cdot is interpretable (REVISION: it is not interpretable)
   -> \ul{...} will automatically switch the proof to Q and interpret the relevant (s(s(s...)))
   -> Switching to Q sets s as a unary operator automatically
   -> There is an option to show numbers instead of (s(s(s...)))
   -> ⋅ is the symbol used internally for multiplication and is interpretable
   -> + is the symbol used internally for addition and is interpretable
- Bonus easter eggs of other things in development



v. 1.2.0 (Major Release)
========================
- Added support for identity rules
- Added support for identity boxes
- Created a new Settings dialog
- Created a list of arities for terms
- Implemented shortcuts for universally quantified implication, equivalence and identity


v. 1.1.2a (Identity Preparation) (ALPHA)
===============================
- Added option to reverse the order of conjuncts in conjunction introduction.
- Input now able to parse = and \neq
- Fixed problem where substituting variables in quantifying could replace letters in commands
- Introduced =I in a simple form (a=a)
- Introduced =I, creating identity boxes, using lines
- Introduced =E, working inside identity boxes and outside
- Added option to change to NK=


v. 1.1.2 (Visuals) (current)
==================
- Added scrollbars
- Added export to plain text, export to png and copy png to clipboard
- Added zoom feature


v. 1.1.1 (Bugfixes)
===================
- Bug where \sequent format would not work if no premises were supplied fixed.
- Incorrect selection of goal after certain applications of negation elimination and equivalence elimination fixed.
- Changed conjunction introduction, when both conjuncts are created as goal. Now each new goal has a blank line above it. This means that every goal always has a blank line above it. This solves problems where new resources were justified by lines below them, blanks failed to collapse and blanks remained once the proof is finished.
- Parsing method changed to give feedback on common errors. Spaces are automatically removed, avoiding one common problem. Instances of \, are now ignored. The normal (not \sequent) mode now allows for commas.
- The == button is now greyed out if the corresponding line is out of scope.
- Falsum can no longer be double negated.
- Negation introduction now selects the newly created resources as the current resource.
- Disjunction introduction now longer allows for introduction from an out of scope disjunct.
- Using universal elimination now moves the current resource to the newly created resource.
- The illegal parameter flag has been changed from !!![just]!!! to [just]!.
- The outputted TeX code now moves the justification if the line length is too long.



v. 1.1.0 (Major Release)
========================
- Expands proof assistant to the NK system.
- Quantifiers are now supported.
- Universal elimination and existential introduction are automatic if the corresponding goal/resource matches. If not, the user is always prompted for a term.
- Universal introduction and existential elimination generate new parameters automatically, by default. The user can change this in the options menu, allowing the user to choose the parameter used. If the parameter is already used in scope, the user is alerted and the justification flagged by !!!. This flagging has been extended to the TeX code.
- Under Options, the user can toggle between NJ and NK. Choosing NK results in a double negation button being present next to all goals. This button works, and double negates the goal.
- The New Proof dialog remembers the text that was previously in it.
- Fixed an error where cancelling New Proof would result in a null pointer exception.
- Changed the undo shortcut to be system portable (I hope).
- Fixed the goal selection after some cases of negation elimination.
- Moved the buttons such that they are aligned with the column of justifications.
- Changed the colour of the goal from blue to green (green for goal, red for resource).




v. 1.0.3 (Bugfixes)
===================
- Fixed a problem where a second assumption scope (for example from a conjunction of implications) would be created inside the first assumption scope. It is now created below the first assumption scope.
- Undo no longer continues back to previous proofs.
- Fixed a problem where blank lines where not disappearing as they should, when two or more blank lines were in the proof.
- Fixed a problem where the goal would not move correctly after some cases of equivalence elimination.
- Equivalence elimination gave an array index out of bounds error when the lefthandside was the goal and the righthandside had not been found. This has been fixed.
- The array index out of bounds exception that occured when clicking outside the proof area has been fixed.
- Added an "About" menu item under Options.


v. 1.0.2 (Undo, Start from Command Line)
========================================
- Added the ability to undo proofs when a mistake has been made. Can be accessed through the menu (Edit -> undo) or by pressing Ctrl+Z
- Allows a proof to be inputted from the command line.
- Fixed a problem where long justifications where not always shown.


v. 1.0.1 (Bugfixes)
===================
- Problem where long lines would be cut off fixed
- Problem where gaps in the proof would sometimes not disappear after applying a rule fixed
- A number of related problems affecting the choice of current goal after applying a rule fixed
- Conjunction Elimination now asks which conjunct you want to use, unless the current goal is one of the conjuncts
- Added the ability to create a proof using the format \sequent{[premises]}{[conclusion]}. The format used is detected automatically.



v. 1.0.0 (Initial Release)
==========================
- Ability to construct NJ proofs using conjunction, disjunction, equivalence, implication and negation
- Input via GUI, using mylogicv02.sty style macros, with conclusion signalled by flag -c
- Proof displayed in GUI with scope lines drawn
- Unjustified lines able to be selected as current goal
- Justified lines above current goal able to be selected as current resource
- Current goal/resource indicated by line colours
- Ability to export proof to TeX code within GUI
- Option to indicate which lines are in scope of current goal